Guide to the Abe Fortas Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Supreme Court Papers, 1946-1970; Series I
  The case files provide a record of each case that the Court accepted for hearing or review. There is no typical file in this series. The materials relating to some cases are contained within a single folder. While such files are generally for cases in which Justice Fortas did not write an opinion, there are still valuable materials in them. They often contain handwritten notes that Justice Fortas took during the conference of all the justices. They also contain carbon copies of memoranda between the justices as to whose opinion a justice chose to join. Justices often changed their minds as opinions went through multiple drafts and circulations, as majority, dissenting, and concurring opinions were proposed, then abandoned, then reformulated. There are often additional memoranda written by Justice Fortas's clerks, as well as various marginal, handwritten notes to and from Fortas and his clerks. Each file concludes with the various printed drafts of all the final opinions involved, including concurring and dissenting opinions. These printed versions were circulated among all the justices and their comments often appear in the margins. The last item in each of the case files is the final, official printed version of the Court's opinion.
  Some cases, especially those in which Justice Fortas wrote one of the opinions, take up multiple files. In addition to the materials noted above, these files usually contain numerous handwritten drafts of the opinions, both in Fortas's hand, and in the hand of his clerks, as well as extensive internal correspondence between Justice Fortas and his clerks. There is also considerable and often quite candid correspondence among the justices, and the more formal memoranda to the conference, the latter of which were circulated among all the justices. There are letters and newspaper clippings sent to Justice Fortas prior to his writing his opinion, as well as after his opinion was published. The letters that Justice Fortas received run the gamut from appreciative fan mail from friends, celebrities, and, most often, simple citizens registering their views, all the way to angry, abusive, "crank" notes regarding his work on the Court. In certain instances, usually when a letter or telegram was particularly odd or even mildly threatening, Fortas specified in his own hand that the correspondence should be saved and set aside, perhaps indicating that some correspondence was not retained. There is often overlap in the included correspondence between his case files and Justice Fortas's active speaking and writing career. People who had seen Fortas speak or read one of his articles or his book on civil rights or civil disobedience, often wrote to the justice regarding a matter with which the Supreme Court was grappling. Justice Fortas's clerks and his office staff also seem to have collected some materials, such as articles, notes, and newspapers clippings, to add to the files and perhaps to aid Justice Fortas's deliberations on a given case.
  In some instances, when cases dealt with similar matters, a decision was made by the justices to link a number of cases together, creating omnibus companion cases. Case files that relate to more than one case are identified by the name and docket number of the first case in the final form of the printed opinion. The docket numbers of the other companion cases appear in brackets in the folder title. In the hectic life of a case before the Court, companion cases are often added and, on a number of occasions, later dropped, and perhaps later added again, as the judicial process continues.
  The next large group of materials in the series are the extensive correspondence and related memoranda and printed materials, such as newspaper and journal articles, that specifically relate to the major events in Justice Fortas's judicial career. The first set of files relate to Fortas's nomination by President Johnson as associate justice of the Supreme Court in 1965. The next set relates to Fortas's nomination as chief justice of the United States in 1968. Correspondence, memoranda, and other materials related to Fortas's withdrawal of his nomination as chief justice in the face of a flurry of controversy and opposition follow. The group concludes with the correspondence and other materials related to Justice Fortas's resignation from the Supreme Court in 1969. Included in these files is the official correspondence between Fortas and President Johnson, President Richard M. Nixon, Chief Justice Earl Warren and other members of the Court, various members of the U.S. Congress, and other government officials, both in support of and in opposition to, Fortas's two nominations. As word spread that Fortas was considering resigning, a large number of people wrote to him, mostly to encourage him not to resign from the Supreme Court. Of particular note here is Fortas's explanation, in a letter to Chief Justice Warren, of the controversies that led to his resignation, as well as handwritten notes of Fortas's conversation with President Nixon on the day of his resignation. There are additional materials that speak to Fortas's resignation from the Court in correspondence and materials in other series, especially the writings series and the correspondence and topical files series.
  - Supreme Court October Term 1965
    - Appellate docket books, Nos. 1-1436 (Box 1, Folder 1 - 33)
    - Appellate docket memoranda
      - Unnumbered (Box 2, Folder 34)
      - Nos. 2-245 (Box 2, Folder 35 - 48)
      - Nos. 246-534 (Box 3, Folder 49 - 64)
      - Nos. 535-956 (Box 4, Folder 65 - 87)
      - Nos. 957-1344 (Box 5, Folder 88 - 105)
    - Miscellaneous docket books, Nos. 1-1831 (Box 5, Folder 106 - 113)
    - Miscellaneous docket memoranda
      - Nos. 1-400 (Box 6, Folder 114 - 139)
      - Nos. 401-898 (Box 7, Folder 140 - 173)
      - Nos. 900-1741 (Box 8, Folder 174 - 219)
    - "Nine Copy" memoranda, Nos. 2-1616 (Box 9, Folder 220 - 226)
    - Administrative files
      - Amendments to Federal Rules of Civil Procedure (Box 9, Folder 227)
      - Amendments to Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure (Box 9, Folder 228)
      - Case assignments (Box 9, Folder 229)
      - Case logbook (Box 9, Folder 230 - 231)
      - Conference list [annotated] (Box 9, Folder 232 - 236)
      - Court statistics (Box 9, Folder 237)
      - Disqualifications, Justice Fortas (Box 9, Folder 238)
      - Docket book, original [Nos. 20-26] (Box 10, Folder 239)
      - In chambers opinions (Box 10, Folder 240)
      - Memoranda and correspondence (Box 10, Folder 241)
      - Per curiam opinions (Box 10, Folder 242)
      - Proposed per curiam opinions (Box 10, Folder 243)
      - Special conference list (Box 10, Folder 244 - 246)
    - Case Files
      - No. 2 U.S. v. Romano (Box 10, Folder 247)
      - No. 3 Albertson v. Subversive Activities Control Board (Box 10, Folder 248)
      - No. 4 Leh v. General Petroleum Corp. (Box 10, Folder 249)
      - No. 5 Shuttlesworth v. City of Birmingham (Box 10, Folder 250)
      - No. 5 Orig. [1964 term] U.S. v. California (Box 10, Folder 251)
      - No. 6 Harris v. U.S. (Box 10, Folder 252)
      - No. 7 Hanna Mining Co. v. District 2, Marine Engineers Beneficial Association (Box 10, Folder 253)
      - No. 9 Swift & Co. v. Wickham (Box 10, Folder 254)
      - No. 9 Orig. U.S. v. Louisiana (Box 10, Folder 255)
      - No. 10 U.S. v. Yazell (Box 10, Folder 256 - 258)
      - Nos. 11, 37, 43, 55 Graham v. John Deere Co. [patent cases] (Box 11, Folder 259 - 260)
      - No. 12 Western Pacific Railroad Co. v. U.S. (Box 11, Folder 261)
      - No. 13 Walker Process v. Food Machinery (Box 11, Folder 262)
      - No. 14 Interstate Commerce Commission v. Atlantic Coast Line (Box 11, Folder 263)
      - No. 14 Orig. Louisiana v. Mississippi (Box 11, Folder 264)
      - No. 15 Federal Trade Commission v. Mary Carter Paint Co. (Box 11, Folder 265)
      - No. 16 Snapp v. Neal (Box 11, Folder 266)
      - No. 17 U.S. v. Speers (Box 11, Folder 267 - 268)
      - Nos. 18, 53 U.A.W. v. Scofield (Box 11, Folder 269)
      - No. 19 Bouligny v. U.S. (Box 11, Folder 270 - 271)
      - No. 20 Carnation v. Pacific Westbound Conference (Box 11, Folder 272)
      - Nos. 21, 22, 26, 32 United Gas v. Gallery Properties [natural gas cases] (Box 11, Folder 273)
      - No. 22 Orig. South Carolina v. Katzenbach (Box 11, Folder 274 - 275)
      - No. 23 Fribourg Navigation Co. v. Commissioner of Internal Revenue (Box 12, Folder 276 - 277)
      - No. 23 Misc. James v. Louisiana (Box 12, Folder 278)
      - No. 25 U.S. v. Johnson (Box 12, Folder 279)
      - No. 27 Gunther v. San Diego & Arizona Eastern Railway Co. (Box 12, Folder 280)
      - No. 28 Katchen v. Landy (Box 12, Folder 281)
      - No. 29 U.S. v. Ewell (Box 12, Folder 282)
      - Nos. 30, 31 Idaho Sheet Metal Works v. Wirtz (Box 12, Folder 283 - 284)
      - No. 38 Rosenblatt v. Baer (Box 12, Folder 285 - 286)
      - No. 40 California v. Buzard (Box 12, Folder 287)
      - No. 41 Brown v. Louisiana (Box 12, Folder 288 - 290)
      - No. 42 Ginzburg v. U.S. (Box 13, Folder 291 - 292)
      - No. 44 Segal v. Rochelle (Box 13, Folder 293)
      - No. 45 Linn v. United Plant Guard Workers of America (Box 13, Folder 294 - 295)
      - No. 46 U.S. v. General Motors Corp. (Box 13, Folder 296 - 299)
      - No. 47 Giaccio v. Pennsylvania (Box 13, Folder 300)
      - No. 48 Harper v. Virginia State Board of Elections (Box 13, Folder 301)
      - No. 49 Mishkin v. New York (Box 13, Folder 302)
      - No. 51 Hicks v. District of Columbia (Box 14, Folder 303 - 306)
      - No. 52 Tehan v. U.S. (Box 14, Folder 307)
      - No. 56 Misc. In Re Harris (Box 14, Folder 308)
      - No. 57 Hazeltine Research v. Brenner (Box 14, Folder 309)
      - No. 58 Brenner v. Manson (Box 14, Folder 310 - 312)
      - Nos. 59, 60 U.S. v. Price
        - Correspondence, notes (Box 14, Folder 313 - 315)
        - Opinion drafts (Box 15, Folder 316 - 318)
      - No. 61 Evans v. Newton (Box 15, Folder 319)
      - No. 63 Consolo v. Federal Maritime Commission (Box 15, Folder 320)
      - No. 65 U.S. v. Guest (Box 15, Folder 321 - 322)
      - Nos. 67, 412, 442 Cheff v. Schnackenberg [contempt cases] (Box 15, Folder 323)
      - Nos. 69, 71 Brotherhood of Locomotive Engineers v. Chicago, Rock Island, and Pacific Railroad Co. (Box 15, Folder 324)
      - Nos. 73, 74, 75, 76, 77 U.S. v. Grinnel et al. (Box 15, Folder 325 - 326)
      - Nos. 73, 74, 75, 76, 77 U.S. v. Grinnel et al. (Box 16, Folder 327 - 328)
      - Nos. 81, 85, 191, 319, 449 WMCA, Inc. v. Lomenzo [New York reapportionment cases] (Box 16, Folder 329)
      - No. 90 Jordan v. Louisiana (Box 16, Folder 330)
      - No. 104 Kent v. U.S. (Box 16, Folder 331 - 334)
      - No. 106 Federal Trade Commission v. Borden (Box 16, Folder 335)
      - No. 118 Federal Trade Commission v. Brown Shoe Co. (Box 16, Folder 336)
      - No. 119 U.S. v. New Orleans Chapter, Associated General Contractors of America (Box 16, Folder 337)
      - No. 123 Jones & Laughlin Steel Corp. v. Gridiron Steel Co. (Box 16, Folder 338)
      - No. 124 Fairfax Family Fund v. California (Box 16, Folder 339)
      - No. 127 U.S. v. O'Malley (Box 16, Folder 340)
      - No. 141 First Security National Bank of Lexington v. U.S. (Box 16, Folder 341)
      - No. 144 Price v. State Road Commission of West Virginia (Box 16, Folder 342)
      - No. 147 Georgia v. Rachel (Box 16, Folder 343)
      - No. 161 Surowitz v. Hilton Hotels Corp. (Box 16, Folder 344)
      - Nos. 210, 290 Stevens v. Marks (Box 16, Folder 345)
      - No. 219 Baxstrom v. Herold (Box 17, Folder 346)
      - No. 224 Simmons v. Union News Co. (Box 17, Folder 347)
      - No. 243 United Mine Workers v. Gibbs (Box 17, Folder 348)
      - No. 256 U.S. v. Cook (Box 17, Folder 349)
      - No. 258 Wells v. Reynolds (Box 17, Folder 350)
      - Nos. 275, 276 Morton Salt Co. v. U.S. (Box 17, Folder 351)
      - No. 280 Accard v. Pennsylvania Railroad Co. (Box 17, Folder 352)
      - No. 282 Amell v. U.S. (Box 17, Folder 353)
      - No. 291 U.S. v. Standard Oil (Box 17, Folder 354)
      - No. 303 U.S. v. Von's Grocery Co. (Box 17, Folder 355)
      - Nos. 318, 323, 409 Burns v. Richardson [Hawaii reapportionment cases] (Box 17, Folder 356)
      - No. 341 Wallis v. Pan American Petroleum Corp. (Box 17, Folder 357)
      - No. 345 U.S. v. Maryland for the Use of Meyer [originally OT 1964] (Box 17, Folder 358)
      - Nos. 345, 508 McClelland v. Texas (Box 17, Folder 359)
      - No. 351 Commissioner of Internal Revenue v. Tellier (Box 17, Folder 360)
      - No. 368 A Book Named "John Cleland's Memoirs of a Woman of Pleasure" v. Attorney General [the "Fanny Hill" case] (Box 17, Folder 361 - 363)
      - No. 369 Misc. Millan-Garcia v. Immigration and Naturalization Service (Box 17, Folder 364)
      - No. 375 Pennsylvania Public Utility Commission v. Pennsylvania Railroad Co. (Box 17, Folder 365)
      - No. 382 Pate v. Robinson (Box 17, Folder 366)
      - No. 387 UAW v. Hoosier Cardinal Corp. (Box 17, Folder 367)
      - No. 396 DeGregory v. Attorney General (Box 17, Folder 368)
      - No. 404 U.S. v. Pabst Brewing Co. (Box 17, Folder 369)
      - Nos. 412, 442 Shillitani v. U.S. (Box 18, Folder 370)
      - Nos. 415, 416 Bradley v. School Board, City of Richmond (Box 18, Folder 371)
      - No. 420 Richmond Television Corp. v. U.S. (Box 18, Folder 372)
      - No. 428 Wetherall v. State Road Commission of West Virginia (Box 18, Folder 373)
      - No. 439 U.S. v. Grace (Box 18, Folder 374)
      - No. 440 U.S. v. Utah Construction and Mining Co. (Box 18, Folder 375)
      - Nos. 471, 649 City of Greenwood, Mississippi v. Peacock (Box 18, Folder 376 - 377)
      - No. 487 Malat v. Riddell (Box 18, Folder 378)
      - No. 490 Sheppard v. Maxwell (Box 18, Folder 379)
      - No. 502 Dennis v. U.S. (Box 18, Folder 380 - 384)
      - No. 505 National Association for the Advancement of Colored People v. Overstreet (Box 18, Folder 385)
      - No. 523 Albanese v. N.V. Nederl. Amerik Stoomv. (Box 18, Folder 386)
      - No. 531 U.S. v. Blue (Box 18, Folder 387)
      - No. 535 U.S. v. Catto (Box 18, Folder 388)
      - No. 545 Seagram v. Hostetter (Box 18, Folder 389)
      - No. 564 Duriron v. Stephenson (Box 19, Folder 390)
      - No. 593 Koehring v. Hyde (Box 19, Folder 391)
      - No. 594 Gojack v. U.S. (Box 19, Folder 392 - 394)
      - No. 597 Mills v. Alabama (Box 19, Folder 395)
      - No. 619 Ashton v. Kentucky (Box 19, Folder 396)
      - No. 636 Securities and Exchange Commission v. New England Electric System (Box 19, Folder 397)
      - No. 645 U.S. v. Equitable Life (Box 19, Folder 398)
      - No. 655 Butts v. Harrison [Virginia poll tax cases] (Box 19, Folder 399)
      - No. 656 Elfbrandt v. Russell (Box 19, Folder 400)
      - No. 657 Brookhart v. Janis (Box 19, Folder 401)
      - No. 658 Schmerber v. California (Box 19, Folder 402 - 403)
      - No. 673 Cardona v. Power (Box 19, Folder 404)
      - No. 680 Nicholas v. U.S. (Box 19, Folder 405)
      - No. 692 Pure Oil Co. v. Suarez (Box 19, Folder 406)
      - No. 694 Perry v. Commerce Loan Co. (Box 19, Folder 407)
      - No. 695 Collier v. U.S. (Box 19, Folder 408)
      - No. 722 Barrios v. Florida (Box 19, Folder 409)
      - Nos. 750, 782, 783 AFL-CIO v. Florida East Coast Railway Co. (Box 19, Folder 410)
      - Nos. 759, 760, 761, 584 [762] Miranda v. Arizona (Box 20, Folder 411 - 414)
      - No. 762 Johnson and Cassidy v. New Jersey (Box 20, Folder 415)
      - No. 815 Davis v. North Carolina (Box 20, Folder 416)
      - No. 818 Hopson v. Texaco (Box 20, Folder 417)
      - No. 835 Harper v. Virginia State Board of Elections (Box 20, Folder 418)
      - Nos. 847, 877 Katzenbach v. Morgan [NewYork voting cases] (Box 20, Folder 419 - 420)
      - No. 890 Clayton Chemical v. U.S. (Box 20, Folder 421)
      - No. 919 Gondeck v. Pan American World Airways (Box 20, Folder 422)
      - No. 940 Rinaldi v. Yeager (Box 20, Folder 423)
      - No. 970 Federal Trade Commission v. Dean Foods Co.
      - Correspondence, dissent drafts (Box 20, Folder 424 - 425)
      - Memo, opinion drafts (Box 21, Folder 426 - 427)
      - No. 1105 Hodes v. U.S. (Box 21, Folder 428)
      - No. 1111 Misc. Chandler v. Judicial Council of The Tenth Circuit (Box 21, Folder 429)
    - "Crank" correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box 21, Folder 430)
  - Supreme Court October Term 1966
    - Appellate docket books, Nos. 1-1469
      - Nos. 1-590 (Box 21, Folder 431 - 446)
      - Nos. 591-1469 (Box 22, Folder 447 - 465)
    - Appellate docket memoranda
      - Unnumbered (Box 22, Folder 466)
      - Nos. 1-200 (Box 22, Folder 467 - 477)
      - Nos. 202-699 (Box 23, Folder 478 - 506)
      - Nos. 702-1272 (Box 24, Folder 507 - 533)
      - Nos. 1276-1435 (Box 25, Folder 534 - 535)
    - Miscellaneous docket books
      - Unnumbered (Box 25, Folder 536)
      - Nos. 1-1846 (Box 25, Folder 537 - 546)
    - Miscellaneous docket memoranda
      - Nos. 10-345 (Box 25, Folder 547 - 566)
      - Nos. 346-880 (Box 26, Folder 567 - 599)
      - Nos. 881-1419 (Box 27, Folder 600 - 631)
      - Nos. 1421-1846 (Box 28, Folder 632 - 647)
    - "Nine Copy" memoranda, Misc. 1-1743 (Box 28, Folder 648 - 654)
    - Administrative files
      - Case assignments (Box 28, Folder 655)
      - Case logbook (Box 28, Folder 656 - 658)
      - Conference lists [annotated]
        - 1966 (Box 28, Folder 659 - 660)
        - 1967 (Box 29, Folder 661 - 663)
      - Court statistics (Box 29, Folder 664)
      - Denials from certiorari (Box 29, Folder 665)
      - Disqualifications, Justice Fortas (Box 29, Folder 666)
      - Docket book, original [Nos. 27-32] (Box 29, Folder 667)
      - In chambers opinions (Box 29, Folder 668)
      - Memoranda and correspondence (Box 29, Folder 669)
      - Orders of the Court (Box 29, Folder 670 - 671)
      - Per curiam opinions (Box 29, Folder 672 - 674)
      - Special conference list (Box 29, Folder 675 - 676)
    - Case Files
      - Nos. 3, 16, 50 Redrup v. New York
        - Opinion drafts (Box 29, Folder 677 - 679)
        - Opinions (Box 30, Folder 680 - 682)
      - No. 3 Misc. Dunning v. Mississippi (Box 30, Folder 683)
      - Nos. 4, 5, 24 Cascade Natural Gas Corp. v. El Paso Natural Gas Co. (Box 30, Folder 684)
      - Nos. 8, 23 Chicago and North Western Railway Co. v. Atchinson, Topeka, and Santa Fe Railway Co. (Box 30, Folder 685)
      - No. 9 U.S. v. Sealy, Inc. (Box 30, Folder 686 - 687)
      - No. 9 Misc. Rees v. Peyton (Box 30, Folder 688)
      - No. 11 Canada Packers v. Atchison, Topeka, and Santa Fe Railway Co. (Box 30, Folder 689)
      - No. 12 Neely v. Eby Construction Co. (Box 30, Folder 690)
      - No. 13, [62] Garrity v. New Jersey (Box 30, Folder 691)
      - Nos. 15, 17, 20 Illinois Central Railroad Co. v. Norfolk and Western Railway Co. (Box 30, Folder 692)
      - No. 16 Austin v. Kentucky (Box 30, Folder 693)
      - No. 18 Utah Pie Co. v. Continental Baking Co. (Box 30, Folder 694)
      - No. 19 Adderley v. Florida (Box 30, Folder 695)
      - No. 22 Time, Inc. v. Hill (Box 31, Folder 696 - 698)
      - No. 22 Time, Inc. v. Hill [material from OT 1965] (Box 31, Folder 699 - 700)
      - No. 22 Time, Inc. v. Hill [material from OT 1966] (Box 31, Folder 701)
      - No. 25 U.S. v. Arnold Schwinn & Co. (Box 31, Folder 702 - 703)
      - No. 27 Giles v. Maryland (Box 31, Folder 704 - 705)
      - No. 27 Giles v. Maryland (Box 32, Folder 706 - 707)
      - No. 28 Transportation-Communication Employees Union v. Union Pacific Railroad Co. (Box 32, Folder 708 - 711)
      - No. 29 Osborn v. U.S. (Box 32, Folder 712)
      - No. 33, 34, 35 Hoffa v. U.S. (Box 32, Folder 713)
      - No. 36 Lewis v. U.S. (Box 32, Folder 714)
      - Nos. 37, 150 Curtis Publishing v. Butts (Box 32, Folder 715 - 717)
      - No. 38 Marchett v. U.S. (Box 33, Folder 718)
      - Nos. 39, 72, 135, 285, 453, 544, 626, 874 Keney v. New York [obscenity cases] (Box 33, Folder 719)
      - No. 39 Abbott Laboratories v. Gardner (Box 33, Folder 720)
      - Nos. 40, 80 Woodby v. Immigration and Naturalization Service (Box 33, Folder 721)
      - No. 41 Costello v. U.S. (Box 33, Folder 722)
      - No. 42 Switzerland Cheese Association v. Horne's Market (Box 33, Folder 723)
      - No. 45 Cichos v. Indiana (Box 33, Folder 724)
      - No. 47 U.S. v. Fabrizio (Box 33, Folder 725)
      - No. 48 Heider v. Michigan Sugar Co. (Box 33, Folder 726)
      - No. 49 United Gas Pipe Line Co. v. Federal Power Commission (Box 33, Folder 727)
      - No. 50 Gent v. Arkansas (Box 33, Folder 728 - 731)
      - Nos. 51, 73, 88 First National Bank of Logan, Utah v. Walker Bank and Trust Co. [Utah cases] (Box 33, Folder 732)
      - No. 52 National Labor Relations Board v. Acme Industrial Co. (Box 33, Folder 733)
      - No. 53 National Labor Relations Board v. C & C Plywood Corp. (Box 33, Folder 734)
      - Nos. 54, 91 Immigration and Naturalization Service v. Errico (Box 33, Folder 735)
      - Nos. 57, 59, 60 American Trucking Associations v. Atchison, Topeka, andSanta Fe Railway Co. (Box 33, Folder 736 - 737)
      - No. 62 Spevack v. Klein (Box 34, Folder 738 - 739)
      - No. 63 Bank of Marin v. England (Box 34, Folder 740)
      - No. 65 Watkins v. Conway (Box 34, Folder 741)
      - No. 66 Berenyi v. Immigration and Naturalization Service (Box 34, Folder 742)
      - No. 67 Travis v. U.S. (Box 34, Folder 743)
      - Nos. 68, 69, 70 Spencer v. Texas [recidivist cases] (Box 34, Folder 744 - 745)
      - No. 75 Misc. Winters v. Beck (Box 34, Folder 746)
      - No. 76 U.S. v. Demko (Box 34, Folder 747)
      - No. 77 Long v. District Court of Iowa (Box 34, Folder 748)
      - No. 78 Department of Employment v. U.S. (Box 34, Folder 749 - 750)
      - Nos. 79, 94 Pierson v. Ray (Box 34, Folder 751)
      - No. 81 Parker v. Gladden (Box 34, Folder 752)
      - No. 83 U.S. v. Robel (Box 34, Folder 753 - 755)
      - No. 84 Lassen v. Arizona Ex Rel. Arizona Highway Department (Box 35, Folder 756)
      - No. 86 U.S. v. Acme Process Equipment Co. (Box 35, Folder 757)
      - No. 87 Bond v. Floyd (Box 35, Folder 758)
      - No. 89 Walker v. Southern Railway Co. (Box 35, Folder 759)
      - No. 91 Misc. Budd v. California (Box 35, Folder 760)
      - No. 92 [180] Camera v. Municipal Court of the City of San Francisco (Box 35, Folder 761)
      - No. 95 Chapman v. California (Box 35, Folder 762)
      - No. 98 Anders v. California (Box 35, Folder 763)
      - No. 100 Klopfer v. North Carolina (Box 35, Folder 764)
      - No. 101 Federal Trade Commission v. Universal-Rundle Corp. (Box 35, Folder 765)
      - No. 103 Cooper v. California (Box 35, Folder 766)
      - No. 105 Keyishian v. Board of Regents of The University of The State of New York (Box 35, Folder 767)
      - Nos. 110, 111 National Woodwork Manufacturers Association v. National Labor Relations Board (Box 35, Folder 768 - 769)
      - No. 114 Vaca v. Sipes (Box 36, Folder 770 - 773)
      - No. 116 In re Gault
        - Case files
          - Drafts, opinions (Box 36, Folder 774 - 779)
          - Opinions, concur and dissent (Box 37, Folder 780 - 783)
        - Correspondence (Box 37, Folder 784 - 785)
        - Juvenile case materials (Box 37, Folder 786)
        - Publications relating to juveniles and law (Box 37, Folder 787)
        - Records and briefs
          - Briefs and Jurisdictional Statement (Box 37, Folder 788)
          - Briefs and Transcript of Record (Box 38, Folder 789)
      - No. 118 Dombrowski v. Eastland (Box 38, Folder 790 - 791)
      - No. 124 Sandoval v. Rattikin (Box 38, Folder 792)
      - Nos. 127, 128 Federal Power Commission v. United Gas Pipe Line Co. (Box 38, Folder 793)
      - No. 136 Swann v. Adams (Box 38, Folder 794)